最近還好嗎，堜龤H
Allora, come stai, Leone?
還不錯
Bene.
讓我們來談生意…
Okay, okay. Let's talk business.
這死胖子想搶莫堹鰶曭漸芛N
This fat bastard is trying to move in on Morizio's business.
你知道，莫堹鰶欓O個講道理的人
And you know, Morizio is a reasonable guy.
他只想談談
He just wants a little conversation.
但這死胖子，什麼也不想聽
But this guy,he don't wanna hear about it.
也許他會聽你的
Maybe he'll listen to you.
他每星期二來城 你星期二有空嗎？
He comes to town every Tuesday. Are you free Tuesday?
我有空
Yeah, I'm free Tuesday.
很高興再見到你，瓊斯先生
Nice to see you again, Mr Jones.
記住，要幹淨俐落
Remember, neatness counts.
給你半小時
You got one half hour.
一小時
One hour.
什麼事？
Yeah, what?
我是唐托，在樓下 有個家夥想跟你談
It's Tonto, downstairs. There's a guy who wants to talk to you.
他長什麼樣子？
What's he look like?
很有敵意
Serious.
- 告訴他，我馬上就上去 - 他上來了
- Tell him I'm coming up. - He's coming up.
有個不懷好意的人要上來了
Somebody's coming up. Somebody serious.
米奇，眼睛睜大些 有人來找茬
Mickey, open your eyes. We got company.
有人來找茬
We got company.
來吧
Come on.
停火！
Stop, stop, man!
唐托
Tonto.
快去告訴司機，在後面等我們
Tell the driver to wait for us out back, and hurry up.
- 甜心，出什麼事了？ - 別擔心，寶貝
- Hey sweetie, what's going on? - Don't worry, baby.
沒事的，再睡會兒吧
It's cool. Take a nap.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
那些混蛋把兩邊的出口都堵住了
Those fuckers blocked both the exits.
檢查一下陽台！
Check the terrace!
- 911緊急事故台 - 快幫幫我
- 911 emergency. - I need help.
- 有人想殺我 - 好的，別掛電話
- Somebody's trying to kill me. - Alright, just stay on the line.
請稍等一下
I'll just be off a moment.
我給你聯絡一位警官
Sir, I'm gonna connect you with an officer.
我是傑佛遜警探 有什麼可以效勞的嗎？
Detective Jefferson. May I help you?
我再打給你
I'll call you back.
冷靜點，老兄 那些箱子埵酗W好的玻利維亞貨
Relax, man. I got half of Bolivia sitting in them suitcases over here.
絕對沒摻過 拿去吧，都是你的了
Ain't been cut yet. Go ahead, take it. It's yours.
打這個電話號碼
Dial this number.
我再跟你聯絡，甜心，好嗎？
I'll talk to you later, sweetie, okay?
再見
Bye.
- 喂 - 我是莫堹鰶齱A記得我嗎？
- Hello? - It's Morizio. Remember me?
- 看來你回到城堣F - 是的，我是說，也不算是
- I see you're back in town. - Yeah. No, I mean, no.
我只待一天
Just for today.
那麼我可以肯定的說 今天是你在城堛熙怮嶀@天…
Aha, so it's safe to say today's your last day in town...
我們再也不會見到 你那張死豬臉了
and we'll never see your fat fucking face again.
是的，沒錯
Yeah. Right.
讓我跟我們共同的朋友說句話
Let me speak to our mutual friend.
他想跟你談
He wants to talk to you.
一定要讓他明白，再放他走
Make sure he understands, and let him go.
你明白了嗎？
Do you understand?
- 說出來 - 我明白了
- So say it. - I understand.
很好
Good.
天啊
Jesus.
跟平常一樣兩盒牛奶？
Hola! Qutal amigo? Two milk as usual, eh?
嗨
Hi.
為什麼要把香煙藏起來？
Why did you hide the cigarette?
這樓埵釩雃h告密者
This building's full of rats.
我不想讓我老爸發現 麻煩夠多了
I didn't want my old man to find out. Got enough problems.
出了什麼事？
What happened?
我騎車不小心摔下來
I fell off my bike.
別告訴我爸我有抽煙，好嗎？
Don't tell my dad about the cigarette, okay?
- 為什麼你要這樣對我們？ - 我不知道…
- Why are you doing this to us? - I don't know--
這年頭人們的記性總是有問題 肯定是太陽的緣故
People got memory problems these days. It must be the sun.
- 幾時該幹嘛都得看太陽 - 我不知道這是怎麼回事
- Know when to come out of the sun. - I don't know how it happened.
我該幹什麼？ 我只負責保管貨
What's my job? I'm just a holder.
我保管你們給我的貨 我連碰都沒碰過它
I hold the stuff you give to me. I don't look at it, I don't touch it.
- 我甚至不知道怎麼摻淡 - 聽我說，好嗎？
- I don't even know how to cut it. - Try to follow me, alright?
六月的時候 我們給你的白粉，純度是100%
In June, we gave you the dope. It tests 100 percent pure.
現在是七月份 我們來拿白粉，純度只有90%
Now it's July, we pick up the dope, and it tests 90 percent pure.
六月到七月之間，10%被摻了！
Somewhere between June and July, ten percent turned to cut!
我不知道，這與我無關 你把東西給我，我幫你保管
I don't know. It's none of my business. You give me the stuff, I hold it.
- 我只知道這些 - 你知道，我想幫你的忙…
- That's all I know. - You know I'm trying to help you out here...
但如果你想對這事死不認帳…
but if you're gonna be a hard-ass about it...
那我就得去打擾他
I gotta disturb him.
當他在聽音樂時 最討厭被別人打擾
When he's into his music, he hates being disturbed.
我說的都是實話
I'm telling you the truth.
希望如此，因為他有辦法分辨真假
I hope so, because he's got a talent for sniffing out a lie.
很嚇人的
It's scary.
他就像是有第六感
It's almost like a sixth sense.
你是想改變說法呢 還是真要我去打擾他？
Are you gonna change your tune or I gotta bust into his?
我說的都是實話
I'm telling you the truth.
好吧
All right.
史丹
Stan.
對不起，他說他沒偷那些白粉
I'm sorry. He said he didn't cut the dope.
他當然沒有
Of course he didn't.
幫我個忙
Just do me a favor.
找出是誰幹的
Find out who did by tomorrow.
在明天中午之前
Noon.
麥基，等一下
Malky, wait.
我沒有偷你的白粉
I didn't cut your shit.
你自己去查吧
Find out yourself!
你在這媟F什麼？ 進去做功課
What are you doing out here? Get inside and do your homework.
- 我早就做好了 - 是嗎？那就進去幫你姐姐…
- I did it already. - Get inside and help your sister...
收拾該死的房子！
clean up the goddamn house!
還有不要再抽煙了！
And stop smoking cigarettes!
一！
One!
二，深吸一口氣
Two. Take a deep breath in.
呼氣
Take a deep breath out.
- 深呼吸 - 時間到了，該我看電視了
- Take a deep breath. Inhale. - Time's up. My turn.
如果轉台，我就打爛你的臉
Change the channel, and I'll smash your face.
現在是腿部運動，下蹲
Ready for the legs. And down.
對不起，甜心
Sorry, sweetheart.
收緊，放松
Squeeze. Release.
早安，瞌睡蟲
Good morning.
嗨，寶貝
Hi, honey.
甜心，把音量關小點，媽媽頭痛
Sweetheart, turn that down. Mama's got a headache.
- 她不讓我換台 - 她只想看該死的卡通！
- She took my turn. - She wants to watch goddamn cartoons!
讓她動動屁股又不會怎樣
It wouldn't hurt her to move her ass.
這埵酗j屁股的人可不是我
I'm not the one with a fat ass around here.
二，起來
Two and up.
那個整天沒事做 只會看卡通的…
Can someone who's doing nothing all day but watching cartoons...
能出去買點吃的回來嗎？
move a little ass and go get some food?
- 腿部運動，漂亮極了 - 看你敢不敢再說一次
- Legs. Beautiful. - I dare you to say that again.
- 瑪姬，我有麻煩了 - 這又不是第一次了
- Margie, I think I screwed up. - It wouldn't be the first time.
你總有辦法解決的，對吧？
You always come up with something, right?
沒錯，但這次我有點過份了
I think I went too far this time.
你現在就很過份 我上班要遲到了
You're going too far right now. I'm gonna be late for work.
今天留在家堣u作，如何？
How about working at home today?
感覺一下 就是那樣，收腹
Really feel it. That's it, stomach in.
- 一… - 看我的！
- One-- - Now it's my turn!
- 媽的！ - 她要打我！
Shit! She's gonna hit me!
- 爸爸，她要… - 媽的！把門關上！
- Daddy, she's-- - Shit! Shut the goddamn door!
請別開槍！
Please don't shoot!
臭婊子
Fucking bitch.
- 密卡登！ - 繃緊全身
- Megatron! - Firm up the whole body.
當你繃緊腿的時候 你大腿的肌肉…
When you use the Quadra-Step, your thigh muscles--
- 誰去接一下電話？ - 我沒空！
- Can somebody answer the phone? - I'm busy!
- 喂 - 我是瑪格麗特·麥考麗斯特…
- Hello? - This is Marguerite McCallister...
紐澤西州懷德伍德市 史賓塞學校的校長
headmistress at the Spencer School in Wildwood, New Jersey.
蘭多先生或太太在家嗎？
Is Mr. or Mrs. Lando home?
我就是
This is she.
蘭多太太 你丈夫送瑪蒂達入學時…
Mrs. Lando, when your husband enrolled Mathilda at Spencer...
他告訴我們她是個問題少女
he told us she had troblems.
正如你所知 我們以改變問題少女聞名
As you know, we pride ourselves on turning troubled girls...
把她們教育成健康、有成就的年輕人
into healthy, productive young women.
但如果她們不來上學 我們就無能為力了
But if they are not here, there is very little we can do.
瑪蒂達未經批准 已有兩星期沒來上課了
Mathilda left school without permission nearly two weeks ago.
雖然你丈夫 已預付了一年的學費…
I know your husband paid tuition in advance for a year...
但學校守則上寫得很清楚…
but if you will refer to the rules and regulations manual we sent you...
學生若長期缺席，除非有請過假…
you will see that unless there is a valid excuse for prolonged absence...
否則預繳的學費不能退回
your tuition will be forfeit.
她死了
She's dead.
叫那小鬼快做點事！
Tell that fucking kid to do a little work around here!
收拾幹淨！ 這媔簽o讓我心煩
Clean up! I'm tired of this fucking mess.
快點！
Hurry up!
我為什麼會覺得
Why am I feeling
當事情看起來毫無希望
When things could look black
沒有什麼會可能出錯
That nothing could possibly go wrong
今天是最不尋常的一天
This has been A most unusual day
愛讓我用另一種方式
Love has made me see things
看清周圍的事物
In a different way
生活是否永遠如此艱辛 還是僅僅童年才如此？
Is life always this hard, or is it just when you're a kid?
總是這樣艱辛的
Always like this.
留著吧
Keep it.
我要去商店買東西 你要我帶些牛奶嗎？
I'm going grocery shopping. You want some milk?
一誇脫還是兩誇脫？ 買兩盒，對嗎？
One quart or two? It's two, right?
我喜歡這種暴風雨前的寧靜時刻
I like these calm little moments before the storm.
這令我想起貝多芬
It reminds me of Beethoven.
你聽到了嗎？
Can you hear it?
就像你把頭放在草地上…
It's like when you put your head to the grass...
你能聽到小草在生長
you can hear it growing.
你能聽到昆蟲的爬行聲
You can hear the insects.
- 你喜歡貝多芬嗎？ - 很難說
- Do you like Beethoven? - Couldn't really say.
我來為你演奏一些
I'm gonna play you some.
爸爸！
Daddy!
你最好待在這
You better stay here.
我們說好是中午的
We said noon.
已經過了一分鍾了
I've got one minute past.
你不喜歡貝多芬
You don't like Beethoven.
你不知道自己錯過了什麼
You don't know what you're missing.
那種序曲令我情緒激昂
Overtures like that get my juices flowing.
如此有力
So powerful.
但序曲之後，說真的…
But after his openings, to be honest...
就變得有點他媽的枯燥
he does tend to get a little fucking boring.
所以我就不聽了！
That's why I stopped!
搜查這屋子
Toss the apartment.
你是莫劄特的樂迷 我也喜歡他
You're a Mozart fan. I love him too.
我愛莫劄特！
I love Mozart!
你知道，他是奧地利人
He was Austrian, you know.
但他這樣的音樂有點輕快
But for this kind of work, he's a little bit light.
所以我比較愛聽震憾一些的
So I tend to go for the heavier guys.
- 酷 - 你他媽的在幹什麼？
- Cool. - Dude, what the fuck are you doing?
老兄，閉上你的臭嘴
Man, keep your bombacut mouth shut.
聽聽布拉姆斯吧，他也不錯
Check out Brahms. He's good too.
- 你他媽的懂什麼音樂？ - 別再吵了！
- What the fuck do you know about music? - Man, knock it off!
- 你檢查過床墊了嗎？ - 沒有
- You check the mattress? - Nope.
喔！他媽的！
Oh! Fuck!
他死了
He's dead.
天啊，看看你幹了什麼！
Jesus. Look what you did.
史丹，你沒事吧？
Stan, you all right?
- 看看你幹了什麼！ - 史丹
- Look what you did. - Stan
史丹，你在幹什麼？
What are you doing?
- 他已經死了！ - 但他毀了我的西裝
- He's dead! - But he ruined my suit.
我知道，但他已經死了
Yeah, I know, but he's dead.
他現在只是一灘爛肉 算了吧，冷靜點
He's a piece of meat. Forget about it. Calm down.
我很冷靜
I'm calm.
留在原地別動，好嗎？
Stay there, all right?
好
Okay.
班尼！
Benny!
天啊，班尼！ 是我和史丹！
Jesus fucking Christ, Benny! It's Malky and Stan!
放輕松，好嗎？
Take it easy, all right?
過來
Come on.
我們出去抽支煙吧
Come on, let's get a cigarette.
班尼，我們要出來了！
Benny, we're coming out!
班尼，別開槍！
Benny, don't fire!
進去！
Get in there!
該死的，班尼！
Jesus fucking Christ, Benny!
你穿著新西裝… 有火嗎？
You wear something new and-- Got a light?
放輕松
Take it easy.
外面發生什麼事了？
What's happening out there?
不要緊，夫人 我們是緝毒署的警察
It's all right, ma'am. D.E.A. Police.
放過那可憐的一家吧
Leave that poor family alone.
- 沒事的，冷靜點 - 我很冷靜，我很冷靜
- Everything's all right. Just calm down. - I am calm. I'm calm.
幹嘛不放過他們呢？
Why don't you leave them alone?
他叫你回屋堨h
He said go back inside.
史丹，不如我們進去吧
Stan, I think it's better if we go inside.
班尼，翻遍廚房 也要找到那些白粉！
Benny, turn that kitchen upside down! Find that shit!
威利，看你幹了什麼！ 你竟然殺死了四歲的小孩！
Willy Blood, look what you did! You killed a 4-year-old kid!
真的有必要這麼做嗎？
Did you really have to do that?
請開門
Please open the door.
求求你
Please.
班尼，應該有三個孩子
Benny, there are three kids here.
史丹殺了這個女孩
I think Stan killed this girl.
威利那混蛋殺了小男孩
Willy, that asshole, shot the little boy.
第三個孩子失蹤了 快去找她
The third one's missing. Find her.
媽的，我們遺漏了一個小女孩
Shit. We missed the little girl, man.
我要去找遍這棟樓房
I'm gonna find the fucking super in this goddamn building.
- 你不認識我嗎？ - 我，鋼索，認識你！
- Don't you recognize me? - Me, Grimlock. Know you!
媽的
Shit.
- 我找到了！ - 太好了！
- Yo! I found it! - Bingo!
- 他們找到白粉了 - 我知道
- They found it. - I know.
在這
There it is.
條子來了，我們最好快走
There's cops outside. We better go.
條子來了 我們得走了，你留在這
It's the cops outside. We better go. You stay here.
我該說些什麼？
What do I say?
告訴他們…
Tell them...
我們在執行公務
we were doing our job.
- 你叫什麼名字？ - 瑪蒂達
- What's your name? - Mathilda.
- 很遺憾你父親死了 - 就算這些人不幹掉他…
- Sorry about your father. - If somebody didn't do it...
哪天我可能也會親自動手
one day or another, I would have probably done it myself.
你媽媽，她…
Your mother, she--
她不是我親生母親
She's not my mother.
我姐姐一心想要減肥 但總不見起色
My sister wanted to lose some weight. Bet she never looked better.
她也不是我親姐姐 只是同父異母的姐姐
She's not even my real sister. Just a half sister.
她不是個好姐姐
Not a good half at that.
既然你受不了他們 那為何還要哭呢？
If you couldn't stand them, why are you crying?
因為他們殺了我弟弟
They killed my brother.
他到底做了什麼？ 他才只有四歲
What the hell did he do? He was four years old.
他不愛哭
He never used to cry.
他只喜歡黏著我
He just used to sit next to me and cuddle.
我比那個臭母豬更像他媽媽
I was more of a mother to him than that goddamned pig ever was.
別那樣罵豬 他們通常比人還要好
Don't talk like that about pigs. They're usually nicer than people.
但它們臭氣薰天
But they smell like shit.
不是的
Not true.
事實上，我廚房奡N有一只…
As a matter of fact, right now I have one in my kitchen...
他很幹淨…
that's very clean...
- 而且味道很香 - 你的廚房堥S有豬
- and smells very nice. - You don't have a pig in your kitchen.
有的
Yes, I do.
我剛去過廚房 沒有看見任何該死的豬
I was just in there, and I didn't see any goddamned pig.
別走開，我去找他
Don't move. I'll get him.
小豬，你在哪堙H
Piggy, where are you?
找到你了
There you are.
嗨，瑪蒂達
Hi, Mathilda.
嗨，小豬
Hi, piggy.
你今天好嗎？
How are you today?
不是太好
I've seen better days.
- 你叫什麼名字？ - 堜
- What's your name? - Leon.
很可愛的名字
Cute name.
你有其他親人 或者可以投靠的地方嗎？
You have anyone to go to, any family anyplace else?
我再去拿點牛奶
I'm gonna get some more milk.
天啊
Holy shit.
別碰那些，拜托
Don't touch that, please.
堜龤A你到底靠什麼維生的？
What do you do for a living?
清潔工
Cleaner.
你的意思是職業殺手？
You're a hit man?
對
Yeah.
真酷
Cool.
- 什麼人都殺嗎？ - 不殺女人和小孩，這是行規
- Do you clean anyone? - No women, no kids. That's the rules.
請人解決那些殺死我弟弟的人渣…
How much would it cost to hire someone to get those dirt bags...
需要多少錢？
who killed my brother?
五千元一個人頭
- Five grand a head. - Wow.
這樣吧，我替你工作…
How about I work for you...
做為交換 你教我如何做「清潔工作」
and in exchange, you teach me how to clean?
你覺得怎麼樣？
What do you think?
我會幫你收拾房間 我會幫你買東西
I'll clean your place. I'll do the shopping.
甚至幫你洗衣服
I'll even wash your clothes.
- 成交嗎？ - 不，我不答應
- Is it a deal? - No, it's not a deal.
你要我怎麼做？ 我已經無處可去了
What do you want me to do? I've got no place to go.
你今天過得真夠受的
You've had a rough day today.
睡覺去吧，明天再說，好嗎？
Go to sleep, and we'll see tomorrow.
你對我真好，堜龤K
You've been really great with me, Leon...
很少有人對我好
and it's not always like that.
你知道嗎？
You know?
晚安
Good night.
睡得好嗎？
You sleep well?
很好
Good.
- 吃完早餐後，你就得離開這 - 去哪堙H
- After breakfast you gotta take off. - Where to?
不關我的事
Not my problem.
讀吧
Read it.
你不識字？
You don't know how to read.
我正在學，但最近工作很忙…
I'm learning, but I've had a lot of work lately...
所以進度有點落後
so I'm a little behind.
上面寫些什麼？
What's it say?
我決定要做個清潔工
I've decided what to do with my life. I wanna be a cleaner.
你要做清潔工？來
You wanna be a cleaner. Here.
拿去吧，這是道別的禮物 去清理吧，但不是跟我
Take it. It's a good-bye gift. Go clean, but not with me.
- 我獨自工作，明白嗎？ - 「雌雄大盜」不是獨自工作
- I work alone. Understand? - Bonnie and Clyde didn't work alone.
「末路狂花」也不單獨行動 他們都是最棒的
Thelma and Louise didn't work alone. They were the best.
瑪蒂達，你為什麼要這樣對我？
Mathilda, why are you doing this to me?
我一直對你很好
I've been nothing but nice to you.
昨天還在門口救了你一命
I saved your life yesterday, right outside the door.
沒錯，所以現在你有責任
Right. Now you're responsible for it.
你救我一定是有理由的
If you saved my life, you must've saved it for a good reason.
現在如果趕我走 就等於昨天你沒開門…
If you throw me out now, it's like you never opened your door...
讓我死在走道上
like you let me die right there in front of it.
但你打開門救了我，所以…
But you did open it. So--
瑪蒂達
Mathilda
如果你不幫我 我今晚就會死，我能感覺到
If you don't help me, I'll die tonight. I can feel it.
我不希望今晚死去
I don't wanna die tonight.
瑪蒂達，你只是個小女孩
You're just a little girl.
請別難過，但我認為你辦不到
Don't take it badly, but I don't think you could do it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
怎麼樣？
How's that?
瑪蒂達…
Mathilda
再那樣做就打破你的腦袋
Don't you ever do that again or I'll break your head.
- 明白了嗎？ - 好的
You got that?
那樣做不夠專業
I don't work like that. It's not professional.
行有行規
There is rules.
好的
Okay.
還有不要一直說「好」，好嗎？
And stop saying okay all the time!
好的
Okay.
很好
Good.
你要在這旅館內用那個東西？
You expect to use that in this hotel?
先生，我必須用它…
Mister, I have to use it...
因為下個月 我要去茱麗亞學院面試…
because I have an audition at Juilliard next month...
我需要練習
and I have to practice.
好吧，但別在十點以後練習
Okay, but not after 10:00.
- 好，我保證 - 好吧
- I promise. - All right.
我讓你們住在走廊盡頭的房間…
I'll put you at the end of the hall...
那樣就不會打擾別人了
so that you don't disturb anyone.
請填妥這張表格
Fill those out, please.
爸爸，讓我來填好嗎？ 我喜歡填旅館的登記表
Daddy, can I please fill them out? I like to check in to hotels.
謝了，老爸，我很快就填好回來
Thanks, Pop. I'll bring these back in a minute.
四樓！
Fourth floor!
謝了，先生！
Thanks, mister!
你真幸運，有個凡事好奇的女兒
You're lucky to have a little girl that's interested in things.
我17歲的兒子還整天遊手好閑
I have a kid, 17, does nothing all day long.
我拿行李上去時 能把這植物暫放在這媔隉H
Can I leave my plant here while I take my stuff upstairs?
當然可以
Of course.
我填上了我最討厭的同學的名字
I'm putting in a name of a girl in my class who makes me sick.
如果出事，她可以當代罪羔羊
If things get hot, she'll take the heat.
填好了
There. Finished.
- 你幾歲了？ - 18歲
- How old are you? - Eighteen.
- 18歲？ - 要看我的身份證嗎？
- Eighteen? - Want to see my license?
不用了，你看起來年輕一些
No. You just look a little young.
謝謝
Thanks.
堜龤A我要你教我如何像你一樣
Leon, I want you to teach me how to be like you.
我要像你一樣強壯和聰明
I want to be strong and smart like you.
瑪蒂達
Mathilda
我知道我還不夠強壯…
I know I'm not strong enough yet...
但我能從基礎學起，理論知識
but I could learn the basics, the theory.
你覺得如何？只是理論知識
What do you think? Just the theory.
我需要這個，堜
I need this, Leon.
我需要時間理清頭緒
I need time to get my head together.
好的，我需要…
Yeah, and I need...
喝的
a drink.
不要動，我去買
Don't move. I'll go get one.
你叫我替你弄這寶貝時…
When you told me to get this baby out for you...
我還以為我聽錯了
I thought my hearing was going.
我告訴自己：「堜軉O個行家 只有初學者才會用到這個東西」
I says to myself, Leon's a pro. Nobody uses that except beginners.
我喜歡保持水准
I like to stay in shape.
當然，永遠保持巔峰
Sure. Always stay on top of it.
像我一樣 我也一定要掌握事情進度
It's like me. I gotta know where everything is all the time.
所以我從不離開這 除非不得不挪地方
I never leave this place, except to go from here to there.
改變不是一件好事 堜龤A你明白嗎？
Change ain't good, Leon. You know?
檢查一下
Check it.
- 確定東西沒錯 - 我信任你
- Make sure it's the right thing. - I trust you.
這兩者不一定有關連，要記住
One thing's got nothing to do with the other. Remember that.
我會記住
I will.
你首先要學會用來福槍…
The rifle is the first weapon you learn how to use...
因為它讓你與目標保持距離
because it lets you keep your distance from the client.
你越專業…
The closer you get to being a pro...
才能越接近目標
the closer you can get to the client.
例如刀子，就是你最後才要學的
The knife, for example, is the last thing you learn.
知道嗎？
Okay?
知道
Okay.
就位
Position.
不對
No.
直到最後一刻才能打開 它會反射亮光
Never take it off until the last minute. It reflects light.
對方在一哩外就能看見你
They can see you coming from a mile away.
永遠穿深色的衣服
And always dress down.
絕不要比地板還明亮，知道嗎？
Never brighter than the floor, okay?
知道
Okay.
開始練習，這是最好的學習方法
Let's practice now. It's the best way to learn.
我該打誰？
Who should I hit?
隨便吧
Whoever.
我馬上來，給我幾分鍾，謝謝
I'll be with you in a second. Give me a few minutes. Thank you.
你們都閃開，我不想看見你們
You guys get lost. I don't want to see you.
- 大家都就位了嗎？ - 要看起來很自然
- Is everyone in position? - This has to look natural.
- 不殺女人和小孩，對嗎？ - 對
- No women, no kids. Right? - Right.
那個穿黃橙色運動服慢跑的人？
Jogger in the yellow and orange?
可以
Okay.
保持冷靜
Keep calm.
視線別離開目標
Don't take your eyes off him.
呼吸放輕松
Breathe easy.
觀察他的動作
Watch his movement.
假想你和他一起在跑
Pretend you're running with him.
試著感受他的下一個動作
Try to feel his next movement.
深呼吸，別動
Take a deep breath. Hold it.
開槍
Now.
我的天啊！
Oh, my God!
- 我沒事，我很好 - 趴下！子彈從哪堮g來的？
- I'm all right. I'm fine. - Get down! Where'd that come from?
一槍命中，不錯吧？
One shot. Not bad, huh?
- 是誰在開槍？ - 我透不過氣了！別壓著我
- Who the hell fired? - I just can't breathe! Get off me.
現在能用真子彈了嗎？
Can we try with real bullets now?
今天不行，我們收工吧
Not today. Let's pack up.
就像這樣
Like that.
- 不，謝了 - 不准討價還價
- No, thanks. - No discussion.
那看起來  像是蘇格拉底
"It seemed to Socrates..."
蘇格拉底…
to Socrates--?
蘇-格-拉-底
So-c-ra-tes.
讓我來
I'll do it.
堜龤A我們一直在工作
Leon, all we do is work.
我們需要休息一下，來玩個遊戲吧
We need a break. Let's play a game.
- 什麼樣的遊戲？ - 我有個很棒的遊戲
- What kind of game? - I have this great game.
有助於思考和記憶 正是你所需要的
It makes you think and helps your memory. It's exactly what you need.
好吧
Okay.
宛如處女
Like a virgin
第一次被男人撫摸
Touched for the very first time
宛如處女…
Like a virgin
- 是誰？ - 我不知道
- Who is it? - I don't know.
好吧
Okay.
祝你生日快樂
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快樂，總統先生
Happy birthday, Mr. President
我不知道
I don't know.
小胡子
Moustache.
我在雨中歡唱
I'm singing in the rain
就在雨中歡唱
Just singing in the rain
- 如此美… - 金凱利？
- What a beaut-- - Gene Kelly?
答對了
Good.
輪到你了
Your turn now.
好吧，朝聖者
Okay, pilgrim.
克林特·伊斯特伍德？
Clint Eastwood?
- 我不知道，我放棄 - 約翰韋恩
- I don't know. I give up. - John Wayne.
我正要說，我發誓 真令人驚奇
I was just about to say that. I swear. It's amazing.
堜龤A你真有才華
Leon, really brilliant.
真令人驚奇
Amazing.
- 你喜歡這盆植物，是嗎？ - 它是我最好的朋友
- You love your plant, don't you? - It's my best friend.
永遠快樂，不問問題
Always happy. No questions.
它就像我…
It's like me, you see.
沒有根
No roots.
如果你真的喜歡它 就該把它種在公園
If you really love it, you should plant it in a park--
它就能落地生根了
so it can have roots.
如果要我成長 那你也應該給我澆水
You should be watering me if you want me to grow.
你說得對
You're right.
等等！
Wait!
得從盤中跳出來，要鮮活
They gotta be jumping out of the plate. They gotta be alive.
好久不見了，堜
It's been a long time, Leon.
我想念你
I missed you.
- 你也錯過了一些好工作 - 我在訓練
- And you missed some nice jobs too. - Been training.
訓練是好事，但別過度了
Training's good, but don't overdo it.
訓練不比工作能賺錢，堜
Training don't pay as good as working, Leon.
湯尼…
Tony...
關於我賺的錢 你幫我保管的那些錢…
all the money I make, that you keep for me--
你需要錢？
You need some money?
不，我只是好奇
Just curious.
我已經工作了很久…
I've been working a long time...
從沒用過那些錢
and I haven't done anything with my money.
也許有一天我會要用那些錢
I thought maybe someday I could use it.
你認識了個女人？
You met a woman.
堜龤A你要小心女人
You gotta be careful with women.
還記得你剛到這國家的時候嗎？
Remember when you arrived in this country?
當我收留你時，你什麼都不懂…
When I took you in, you were still wet behind the fucking ears...
那時你為了個女人惹了一身麻煩
and, already, you were in deep shit because of a woman.
- 別忘了，堜 - 有時我希望能忘掉
- Don't forget that, Leon. - I wish I could sometimes.
你知道，關於我那些錢…
You know, about my money--
也許我…也許我可以…
Maybe I could give...
拿一點出來…
a little...
給別人
to someone.
你知道，去幫助別人
You know, to help out.
這是你的錢，我只是幫你保管 就像是銀行一樣
It's your money. I'm just holding it for you, like a bank.
但比銀行好 因為銀行經常會被打劫
Except better than a bank because banks always get knocked off.
而沒人敢打劫老湯尼
No one knocks off old Tony.
而且，錢存銀行…
Besides, with a bank...
就經常有無數的表格要填
there's always tons of forms and all that shit.
但老湯尼這堙A不用讀，不用寫 全都記在我腦子
But old Tony, nothing to read, nothing to write. It's all in his head.
我現在識字了
I know how to read now.
那很好，堜
That's good, Leon.
你的錢就在這
Your money's here.
無論你何時想要，只要告訴我一聲
Whenever you want it, you just ask me.
- 這埵酗@千元 - 沒關系，我不需要
- Here's a grand. Come on. - It's okay. I don't need it.
- 拿去吧，去找點樂子，拿著 - 謝謝
- Take it. Have some fun. Go ahead. - Thank you.
好吧，現在我們來談生意
All right. Now let's talk business.
別走開，我去拿資料
Don't move. I'll go get the file.
馬諾洛，給我朋友堜蠿茠M牛奶
Manolo, a glass of milk for my friend Leon here.
聽著，瑪蒂達，你要小心
Listen, Mathilda, you gotta be careful.
你不能隨便跟街上的人聊天
You can't just speak to any guy off the street.
堜龤A別緊張 有什麼他媽大不了的？
Leon, get a grip. What's the big fucking deal?
我只是邊等邊抽煙而已
I was just smoking a butt while I was waiting.
我要你戒掉髒話
I want you to stop cursing.
你不能一直這樣跟別人交談
You can't talk to people like that all the time.
我要你努力學習好好說話
I want you to make an effort to talk nice.
好的
Okay.
我要你把煙戒掉，抽煙危害健康
And I want you to stop smoking. It will kill you.
好的
Okay.
離他遠點，他看起來像個怪人
Stay away from him. He looks like a weirdo.
好的
Okay.
我過五分鍾就出來 待在我視線範圍之內
I'll be out in five minutes. Stand where I can see you.
好的
Okay.
堜龤A我想我愛上你了
Leon, I think I'm kinda falling in love with you.
這是我的初戀，你知道嗎？
It's the first time for me, you know.
你從沒談過戀愛 怎麼知道這是愛？
How do you know it's love if you've never been in love before?
因為我感覺到
'Cause I feel it.
哪堙H
Where?
在我肚子堙K
In my stomach.
暖暖的
It's all warm.
以前我老是胃痛 但現在沒有了
I always had a knot there, and now it's gone.
瑪蒂達，我很高興你不再胃痛了
Mathilda, I'm glad you don't have a stomachache anymore.
但那並不代表什麼
I don't think it means anything.
我要遲到了 我討厭工作時遲到
I'm late for work. I hate being late for work.
你女兒的小提琴練得怎樣了？
How's the practicing going?
- 今天過得好嗎，小姐？ - 我有點厭倦練習了
- How are we today, miss? - A little sick of practicing.
我了解
I understand.
但你做得不錯
But you're doing all right.
我沒有接到任何投訴
I haven't received any complaints.
我在弦上放塊布減少噪音
I put a cloth over the strings to lessen the noise.
那真聰明
That's very smart.
- 不是所有人都愛音樂 - 我知道
- Not everyone loves music. - I know.
你父親到底是做什麼的？
What does your father do?
- 他是個作曲家 - 真了不起
- He's a composer. - That's wonderful.
他其實不是我父親
Except he's not really my father.
他是我的愛人
He's my lover.
我要去散步
Think I'll go for a walk.
- 星期六晚上你要做什麼？ - 共進晚餐好嗎？
- What are you doing Saturday night? - What about dinner?
- 嘿，你要去哪堙H - 探訪6樓J室的朋友
- Where you going? - Visiting friends at 6J .
好，去吧 星期六怎麼樣？
Go ahead. What about Saturday?
- 晚上八點？ - 我不知道
- About 8:00? - I don't know.
你已經有約了？
You got plans?
在這婺I頭？
Meet you here?
我們知道你是個忙人 我們會長話短說
We know you're a busy man. We'll make this short.
你只須說清楚當天發生的一切
If you'll just take us step-by-step through exactly what happened.
那人站在這堙A取出槍來
The guy was here. He went for his gun.
我們就向他開槍
Bang, we shot him.
- 那些小孩當時在哪堙H - 我不知道！
- Where exactly were the kids? - I don't know!
他們應該在學校堙A不是嗎？
They should have been at school, don't you think?
你證詞說你是第一個到達的人
Your statement said you were the first man in.
- 你沒看見有小孩嗎？ - 門被砸壞了
- Didn't you see any kids? - The door was broken.
發生什麼事了？ 你有依照程序辦事嗎？
What happened? Did you follow the procedure?
我失去了一個好弟兄 你們他媽的要我怎麼樣？
I lost a good man here. What the fuck do you want with me?
要你合作
Cooperation.
我沒時間談這些無聊的廢話！
I haven't got time for this Mickey Mouse bullshit!
你們想要我合作？ 到我辦公室來，4602室
You want cooperation? Come up in my office, room 4602.
孩子們應該到學校去
Kids should be at school.
拜托，那是我的球！
Come on, that's my ball!
還給我 你要去哪堙H
Give that back. Where you going?
該死！你要去哪堙H 那是我的球！
Damn! Where you going, man? That's my ball!
跟著那輛藍色的車
Follow the blue car.
你要我開響音樂和闖紅燈嗎？
You want me to blast the music and go through the lights?
不，慢慢開
No, drive slowly.
一百塊拿去，閉上你的狗嘴，好嗎？
Take the hundred bucks, and shut the fuck up.
我不想跟你斗 但你逼得我別無選擇
I do not want to fight you, but you leave me no choice.
孩子，你讓我茅塞頓開！
Boy, you just gave me a great idea!
- 有了好主意！ - 歡迎收看每日娛樂新聞…
- I mean a big one! - Welcome back to E! News Daily...
我們30分鍾的最新娛樂報導
our 30-minute look at the latest in entertainment news.
我是碧安卡法拉
I'm Bianca Ferrar.
送給你的，一件禮物
It's for you. A present.
你要我打開嗎？ 我來打開吧
Do you want me to open it? I'll open it.
你喜歡嗎？ 很漂亮，是嗎？
How do you like it? Nice, eh?
麥葛芬先生？
Mr. McGuffin?
我能跟你談談嗎？
Can I have a word with you?
這是報酬，兩萬元，對嗎？
Here. It's for a contract. Twenty grand, right?
他名叫諾曼·史丹菲爾德 他在緝毒署…
His name is Norman Stansfield, and he's in room 4602...
4602室，聯邦廣場26號
in the D.E.A. building, 26 Federal Plaza.
- 我不接受 - 為什麼？
- I'm not taking it. - Why not?
- 我幹不了 - 那好吧
- It's too heavy. - Well.
你能把你的槍租給我一天嗎？
Will you rent me your gear for the day?
我從不出借我的槍
I never lend out my gear.
但…
But...
你可以用你自己的槍
you still have your gun. Use it.
幫我個忙，不要向窗外亂射
Just do me a favor. Don't shoot out the window.
你為什麼要這樣對我？
Why are you so mean to me?
瘋狂地去殺你毫不在乎的人…
Wildly killing people you don't give a shit about...
卻不肯去殺那些 殺了我全家的混蛋？
but you won't get the bastards that killed my whole family?
相信我，複仇不是件好事
Revenge is not good once you're done. Believe.
- 最好是忘掉仇恨 - 忘掉？
- It's better to forget. - Forget?
在我看見我弟弟的屍體 在地板上的輪廓後…
After I've seen the outline of my brother's body on the floor...
你期望我忘掉？
you expect me to forget?
我要殺死那些狗雜種
I want to kill those sons of bitches.
打爛他們的腦袋
Blow their fucking heads off.
你殺了人以後，一切都不一樣了
Nothing's the same after you've killed someone.
你的生活會永遠改變
Your life is changed forever.
今後你睡覺時 都得睜著一只眼睛
You have to sleep with one eye open for the rest of your life.
我不在乎睡什麼覺，堜
I don't give a shit about sleeping, Leon.
我想要愛…
I want love...
或者死亡
or death.
就是這樣
That's it.
我想要死亡
I want death.
別來煩我了，瑪蒂達 我已經厭倦了你的遊戲
Get off my case, Mathilda. I'm tired of your games.
這遊戲真的很棒，堜
There's this really great game, Leon.
它讓人變得更好，讓人開始思考
Makes people nicer. Starts them thinking.
你喜歡的那種遊戲
The kind of game you love.
如果我贏了…
If I win...
你得讓我跟著你…一輩子
you keep me with you... for life.
如果你輸了呢？
And if you lose?
你和以前一樣，自己去買東西
Go shopping alone, like before.
你會輸的，瑪蒂達
You're gonna lose, Mathilda.
槍膛埵酗@顆子彈，我聽出來了
There's a round in the chamber. I heard it.
那又怎樣？
So what?
如果我腦袋中槍死了，你會怎樣？
What's it to you if I end up with a bullet in the head?
沒什麼
Nothing.
我希望你沒說謊，堜
I hope you're not lying, Leon.
我真的希望 你內心深處也沒有愛過我
I really hope that deep down inside there's no love in you.
因為如果你…
Because if there is...
有那麼一點點愛我的話…
just a little bit of love in there for me...
那麼幾分鍾後，你就會後悔 從沒說出自己真正的感受
I think that in a few minutes you'll regret you never said anything.
我愛你，堜
I love you, Leon.
我贏了
I win.
我受傷了
I took a hit.
現在我需要個幫手
I need a hand now.
我知道她還很小，但她學得很快
I know she's young, but she learns fast.
小孩需要培養，對嗎？
Kids need to be shaped into something, right?
我知道，那是我教你的 但是難道沒有年齡限制嗎？
I know. I taught you that. But ain't there an age limit?
她已經18歲了
She's 18.
真的嗎？
Really?
來點喝的好嗎，湯尼？
How about something to drink, Tony?
好的，馬諾洛，給堜蠿茠M牛奶
Sure. Manolo, glass of milk for Leon.
不錯的刺青
Nice tattoo.
馬諾洛，兩杯牛奶
Manolo, make that two.
- 幹嘛要戴帽子？ - 我可不能感冒
- What's that for? - Can't afford to catch cold.
首先，找出門鏈在哪
First you find out where the chain is.
雖然看不見，但你能感覺得到 這
You can't see it, but you can feel it. Here.
- 我按門鈴，你跟他說話 - 我該說些什麼？
- I'll ring, you start talking. - What do I say?
隨你喜歡
Whatever you want.
- 誰？ - 嗨
- Yes? - Hi.
我是蘇珊
It's Susan.
抱歉，你一定是找錯門了，小姑娘
I'm sorry. You must have the wrong door, little girl.
我不認識什麼蘇珊
I don't know any Susan.
退後點，我什麼都看不見
Move back a little. I can't see anything.
走道的燈沒開
The light's out.
外面一片漆黑
It's all dark out here.
- 先生，我很害怕 - 好吧
- Mister, I'm scared. - Okay.
你他媽的想幹什麼？
What the fuck are you doing?
張開嘴
Open up.
如果它離開了你嘴巴 我就扣扳機，明白了嗎？
If it leaves your mouth, I'll pull the trigger, capisce?
沒問題了，把嘴挪開
Here's okay. Let it go.
我說：「把嘴挪開」
I said, Let it go.
走，到那邊去
Move. Move over.
放輕松
Easy. Easy.
小心點，你想要我…
Easy. Careful. You want me--
上吧，輪到你了
Go ahead. Your turn.
救命，求你別殺我
Help me. Please don't beat me.
先生？
Sir?
先生，那些白粉不是我的
Sir, it's not my dope.
先生，聽著，我…
Sir, look I--
請往左邊一點
A little left, please.
在開槍之前…
Before-- Ple--
現在再開一槍，確保目標死亡
Now, the security shot.
不，第二槍要射在胸口上方
No, the second goes higher on the chest.
瞄准心髒和肺
Aim for the heart and lungs.
就是那堙A明白了嗎？
There. Right there. You see?
第一槍打倒目標
The first shot takes him out of order.
- 第二槍就解決他 - 你們他媽的在幹什麼？
- The second finishes him off. - What are you fucking doing?
千萬別射臉
Never in the face.
如果目標無法辨認 你就拿不到酬金
If they can't recognize the client, you don't get paid.
因為你可以隨便找個替死鬼來交差
You could take out anybody and said you did the job.
- 明白了嗎？ - 明白了，別射臉
- Got it? - Got it. Never in the face.
- 現在你可以把槍收起來 - 你們在幹什麼？
- Now you can put the tools away. - What are you fucking doing?
這到底是怎麼回事？ 嘿，先生！
What the fuck is going on? Hey, mister!
你們…
What are you fucking--
如果經常用消音器的話…
You see, when you use the silencer a lot...
你要在這堜騅竷活K
you have to put a piece of cloth here...
因為發熱會使堶捫N起來
because it gets very hot and could burn it inside.
最好是塊濕布，黑色的布
A damp, black cloth is the best.
你在做什麼？
What you doing?
我們說過，不殺女人和小孩
We said no women, no kids.
你以為這些東西會害死誰 那些癮君子嗎？
Who do you think this is gonna kill, junkies and monkeys?
毒物都清理完畢了
Now it's clean.
我們走吧
Let's get out of here.
我還以為我們不應該喝酒
I thought we don't have the right to drink.
我知道，但今天例外 為了慶祝你的首次出擊
I know, but we're making an exception for your first time.
既然我們是在慶祝 出色地完成任務…
Well, if we're making exceptions for a job well-done...
那就吻我一下 就像電影堥獐芊A如何？
how about a kiss, like in the movies?
好吧
Yes.
你想幹什麼？
What you doing?
- 我要吻你 - 快停止，拜托
- I'm going to kiss you. - I want you to stop, please.
來吧，只是吻一下而已
Come on. Just a kiss.
停下，別人都在看著我們
Stop. Everyone is watching us.
回去坐下
Go sit down.
好好享受
Enjoy.
- 你不相信我，是嗎？ - 這話怎麼說？
- You don't believe me, do you? - How's that?
- 我說我愛上你的時候 - 瑪蒂達，請別再說了
- When I say I'm in love with you. - Mathilda, please drop it.
- 換個話題，好嗎？ - 好吧，對不起
- Just change the subject, okay? - Okay. Sorry.
那麼，你第一次殺人時幾歲？
So, how old were you when you made your first hit?
19歲
Nineteen.
那我贏你了
Beat you.
- 你在幹什麼？ - 我可不能感冒
- What you doing? - Can't afford to catch a cold.
- 沒有門鈴 - 那就敲門吧
- There's no doorbell. - So knock on the door.
- 誰？ - 嗨
- Yes? - Hi.
我在找瑞本先生的房間…
I'm looking for Mr. Reuben's apartment...
但走廊一片漆黑，我迷路了
but it's all dark out here in the hall, and I'm lost.
等一下
Just a second.
還要嗎？來啊，露出臉來啊！
You want more? Come on. Show your fucking face.
你以為那麼容易就能殺了我嗎？
You think you're going to get me that easily?
碰到這麼難纏的目標 你就知道任務很棘手
When it's tough like this, you know it's gonna be ugly.
最好盡快搞定它 否則我們會聽他嘮叨一整天
Better make it quick or else we'll be all day listening to his crap.
混蛋！來啊，露出臉來啊！
Asshole! Come on, show me your fucking face, faggot!
- 來啊，口香糖的小把戲 - 嘿
- Come on, gum trick. - Hey.
那麼拉環的把戲呢？你聽說過嗎？
What about the ring trick? You know that one?
拉環的把戲？ 來啊，混蛋，我等著呢
Ring trick? Come on, asshole. I'm waiting.
讓我瞧瞧啊，你他媽的
Show it to me, motherfucker.
這就是拉環的把戲
That's the ring trick.
馬媔齱A回理發店去 晚點再理發
Mario, go back to the barbershop. We'll finish later.
堜龤A怎麼樣？都辦妥了嗎？
Leon, what's up? All done already?
豬比人還要好，對吧？
Nicer than people, eh?
是我告訴你的
I told you that.
- 你遇到麻煩了嗎？ - 沒有
You got a problem?
拿把椅子坐下
Get the chair. Sit down.
我在想…
I was thinking.
如果我哪天出事了…
If something happens to me someday--
嘿，堜龤A你不會出事的
Hey, Leon, nothing's gonna happen to you.
你是所向無敵的 你與子彈共舞
You're indestructible. Bullets slide off you. You play with 'em.
湯尼，我想過錢的事
Tony, I thought about my money.
你記得那天來過的女孩子嗎？
You remember the girl who came here the other day?
她名叫瑪蒂達
Her name is Mathilda.
如果我出事…
If anything happens to me...
我要你…
I'd like you...
把我的錢…
to give her...
都給她
my money.
你可以信賴我，堜
You can count on me, Leon.
謝謝你，湯尼
Thank you, Tony.
我不會太久
I won't be long.
- 我做錯什麼事了嗎？ - 沒有
- Did I do something wrong? - No.
這一票太大了
This one is too big.
我只配幹些「雜活」，對嗎？
Yeah, and I only get the leftovers, is that it?
瑪蒂達，自從我遇見你之後…
Mathilda, since I met you...
一切都跟以前不同了
everything's been different.
所以我只需要一些時間獨處
So I just need some time alone.
你也需要一些時間成長
You need some time to grow up a little.
我結束成長了，堜
I finished growing up, Leon.
現在只是變老
I just get older.
對我而言，剛好相反 我年紀夠大了
For me it's the opposite. I'm old enough.
我需要時間成長
I need time to grow up.
媽的
Shit.
快點！傳球！
Come on! Hustle!
- 好球 - 來吧
- Good shot. - Come on.
你是新來的，不是嗎？ 住在五樓，對嗎？
You're new, aren't you? Fifth floor, right?
- 你不能就那樣坐在這 - 真的嗎，為什麼？
- You can't sit here like that. - Really, why not?
沒有東西是免費的 就像停車計時器
Nothing's free. Like a parking meter.
當你停車時就要付錢 這是規矩
When you stop, you pay. It's the law.
- 只在電視上見過 - 你說什麼？
- Only on T.V. - What'd you say?
- 算了，要給多少錢？ - 十元…
- Forget it. How much is your meter? - Ten dollars...
每個月
a month.
有錢找嗎？
Got change?
別擔心，我可以先付一年的錢
Don't worry about it. We'll do ten for twelve.
我先付今年剩下的，好嗎？
I'll pay now for the rest of the year.
好吧，一年
Okay, a year.
我付了錢還要容忍你們嗎？
Does paying rent here mean I have to put up with you guys?
不
No.
那就到別的地方去玩
So go play somewhere else.
我要思考
I need to think.
起來，你不喜歡你的工作嗎？
Stand up. Don't you like your job?
食物
Food.
- 你要去哪堙H - 送外賣，4602室
- Where you going? - Special delivery, room 4602.
在這媄戚茼W
Sign here.
到這堥
Come here.
- 周末愉快，女孩們 - 謝謝
- Have a nice weekend, girls. - Thanks.
我要去洗手間
I'm gonna go to the restroom.
外賣？
Special delivery?
讓我猜猜看
Let me guess.
中國菜？
Chinese?
也許是泰國菜？
Thai, maybe?
我知道了
I've got it.
意大利菜
Italian food.
你叫什麼名字，小天使？
What's your name, angel?
瑪蒂達
Mathilda
把袋子放在地上
I want you to put the sack on the floor.
很好
Good.
告訴我你所知道的 有關意大利菜的事
Now I want you to tell me everything you know about Italian food.
別忘了提廚師的名字
Don't forget the name of the chef who fixed it for me.
沒人派我來的，我為我自己工作
Nobody sent me. I do business for myself.
那麼就是…
So this is something...
私人恩怨，是嗎？
personal, is it?
我這次又幹了什麼壞事？
What filthy piece of shit...
你殺了我弟弟
did I do now? You killed my brother.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你想去陪他？
And you wanna join him?
不
No.
總是這樣
It's always the same thing.
當你開始真正恐懼死亡的時候…
It's when you start to become really afraid of death...
你才會懂得珍惜生命
that you learn to appreciate life.
你喜愛生命嗎，甜心？
Do you like life, sweetheart?
是的
Yes.
很好
That's good.
因為我不喜歡…
Because I take no pleasure...
去殺一個…
in taking a life...
不在乎生命的人
if it's from a person who doesn't care about it.
史丹
Stan.
史丹，我到處在找你
Stan, I've been looking all over for you.
- 我樓上樓下都找遍了… - 什麼事？我在忙
- I checked upstairs-- - What? I'm busy.
是麥基，他死了
It's Malky, man. He's dead.
麥基代表我們向中國佬買貨
Malky was making a buy for us from the Chinaman.
但他們與此事無關
But they got nothing to do with it.
他們說這家夥從外面闖進來 他是個行家
They told me this guy came from the outside. He was a pro.
身手敏捷，神出鬼沒
He was fast. He fucking came out of nowhere.
兩秒鍾就幹掉了那些中國佬
Boom, shoots the Chinaman dead in two seconds.
別緊張，老兄，我是條子
Easy, man. I'm a cop.
然後他轉過身，對麥基說…
Then turns around, says something to Malky like--
不殺女人，不殺小孩
No women, no kids.
我認為這是私人恩怨
I think it was something personal.
今天死神反覆無常
Death is whimsical today.
老布，你聽到嗎？
Blood, do you hear me?
我聽到了，史丹 冷靜點，老兄
Yeah, I hear you, Stan. Just chill out, man.
帶她去我的辦公室，好嗎？
Would you take her up to my office?
好的
All right.
天殺的
Jesus fucking Christ.
「堜龤A我的愛人」
Leon, my love.
「我知道殺死我弟弟的人在哪堙v
I know where to find the guys who killed my brother.
「他們的頭目名叫諾曼·史丹菲爾德 他在緝毒署，4602室」
Their boss is Norman Stansfield. He's in the D.E.A. building, room 4602.
「我要親手幹掉他們」
I'm gonna do them myself.
「如果我出事的話，桌上有兩萬元」
If something goes wrong, I left you 20 grand on the table.
「那是給你的報酬 殺一個人五千，對嗎？」
It's for a contract. Five grand ahead, right?
「親自解決這件事 我心媟|舒服一些」
I know I'll feel better after I do this.
「我愛你，瑪蒂達上」
I love you.
等我，不會很久
Wait. I won't be long.
我不能在聯邦大樓前停車！
I can't park in front like this. It's a federal building!
他會照我說的話去做
He's gonna do the same exact thing that I said.
九厘米手槍
A nine millie.
子彈
Bullets.
又一把九厘米手槍
Another nine millie.
你打算用這些槍幹嘛？
What'd you plan to do with all these guns?
也許她打算轟掉整棟大樓
Maybe she was planning on taking out the whole building.
天啊！
Holy shit!
這是什麼？午餐
What's this? Lunch.
小心，老布，可能有毒
Careful, Blood, might be poisoned.
不會吧，堶惜S沒有鯷魚
There's no anchovies on this.
你這叫「不會很久」？ 我已經繞了至少十分鍾
Is that what you call I won't be long? I been here for ten minutes.
我已經盡快了，開車吧
I did my best.
你喜歡嗎？
Do you like it?
是的
Yes.
那就說吧
So say it.
我喜歡
I like it.
你不渴嗎？
Not thirsty?
你知道，一個女孩的第一次 是很重要的
You know, a girl's first time is very important.
會決定她以後的性生活
It determines the rest of her life sexually.
我在我姐姐的雜志上看到的
I read that once in one of my sister's magazines.
我的朋友們說 她們討厭第一次的經驗
My girlfriends told me they hated their first experience.
那是因為她們不喜歡做愛的對象
That's because they didn't love the guys.
她們那麼做，只是為了炫耀
They just did it to show off.
後來，她們開始喜歡做愛了 就像抽煙一樣
Afterwards, they started liking it, like cigarettes.
我會第一次就喜歡上做愛嗎？
Will I like it the first time?
瑪蒂達，不行
Mathilda, no.
為什麼？
Why not?
我不能這麼做
I just can't.
- 你愛著別人？ - 沒有
- You love someone else? - No.
我的意思是…
I mean--
很久以前，我愛過一個人
There was someone a long time ago.
在我來美國之前
Before I came to the States.
她父親不准她見我
Her father didn't want her to see me.
她出身高貴的家庭
She was from a very respectable family.
而我…
Mine was...
你知道…
you know...
出身貧寒
not so respectable.
每次她來見我，她爸爸就會發怒
Her dad went nuts every time she'd take off to see me.
她仍然偷偷來見你，對嗎？
She still snuck off to see you, right?
對
Right.
看，愛情是無法阻擋的，堜
See, nothing can stop love, Leon.
他殺了她
He killed her.
一槍擊中她頭部
One shot through the head.
他在監獄堳搕F兩天 就被放了出來
They kept him in jail for two days, and they let him go free.
他們說這是場意外
They said it was an accident.
所以…
So...
一天晚上，我…
one night I...
等著他
waited for him.
帶著來福槍，有五百英尺遠
Five hundred feet with a lens.
他也遇上了「意外」
He also had an accident.
那天晚上我坐上船，來了這堙K
The same night I took a boat and came here...
和我爸爸碰面 他那時在幫湯尼做事
to meet up with my father who was working for Tony.
那年我只有19歲
I was 19.
從那以後，我就沒離開過這城市…
Since then I've never left the city, and...
而且我再也沒有交過女朋友
I've never had another girlfriend.
你明白，瑪蒂達…
You see, Mathilda...
我不會是個好情人的
I wouldn't be a good lover.
好吧
Okay.
你能幫我做件事嗎？
Would you do me one favor?
什麼事？
What?
我討厭看你睡在椅子上
I'm sick of watching you sleep on your chair.
我們一起睡在床上吧
We're gonna share the bed.
我不認為這是個好主意
I don't think it's a good idea.
沒事的
It's okay.
把腿放在床上
Put your legs up on the bed.
很好
Yeah. That's nice.
把頭放低點，沒事的，放輕松
Put your head down. It's okay. Relax.
晚安，堜
Good night, Leon.
晚安
Good night.
先給我一塊蛋糕！
I want a piece of cake first!
馬諾洛，帶孩子們去廚房
Manolo, take the kids in the kitchen.
我一直很尊重你的生意，湯尼
I have a lot of respect for your business, Tony.
你以前為我們殺人…
When you've killed for us in the past...
我們一向都很滿意
we've always been satisfied.
所以今天我很難啟齒
That's exactly why today is going to be very hard for me.
希望你能諒解我的心情
I hope you'll excuse my mood.
我的手下在你的地盤上被殺
My man was killed right here on your turf.
中國佬說，那個殺手…
The Chinks tell me that the hit man...
像是意大利人
was kind of the Italian type.
所以我們想，湯尼可能知道些什麼
So we figured that Tony might know something.
等等，還有件事…
Wait. There's more.
你會喜歡這個的
You're gonna love this.
幾個小時後，一個12歲的小女孩 走進我的辦公室…
A few hours later, a little 12-year-old girl comes into my office...
她全副武裝，想置我於死地
armed to the teeth, with the firm intention of sending me to the morgue.
你知道是誰來把她救走的嗎？
Do you know who came and got her right there in my building?
正是同一個…
The very same...
意大利殺手
Italian hit man.
我真想和他見見面
I'm dying to meet him.
放輕松點，一切都很好 睡得好嗎？
Relax. Everything's fine. Sleep well?
我從沒真正睡著 總會睜著一只眼睛
I never really sleep. Got one eye open always.
是啊，我忘了
Yeah, I forgot.
我從沒見過 有人睜著一只眼還會打鼾
I never saw someone with one eye open snore so much.
- 我打鼾嗎？ - 就像個嬰兒
- I snore? - Like a baby.
我去買些牛奶回來做早餐 很快就回來
I'm gonna get some milk for breakfast. I won't be long.
回來時別忘了敲暗號
Don't forget the code when you come back.
敲兩下，然後一下，再兩下，對嗎？
Two knocks, then one, and two knocks again. Right?
對
Right.
I'm gonna go get some milk.
Hola se駉r! Ring these up. 你好，先生，等一下 我去拿些牛奶
從現在起，不准出聲
From here on out, you don't make a sound.
用點頭或搖頭來回答我的問題 明白了嗎？
You answer my questions by nodding yes or shaking your head no.
他是獨自一人嗎？
Is he alone?
他在等你回去？
Does he expect you?
你有房間鑰匙嗎？
Do you have keys to the apartment?
有沒有敲門的暗號？
Is there a code, a way of knocking, so he knows it's you?
阿爾發小組
Alpha team.
- 最後位置，准備行動 - 小心點
- Final position. We're ready to go. - Be careful.
怎麼了？走開！媽的
What up? Move! Fuck.
糟了
Shit.
阿爾發小組，有人倒地
Alpha team. Man down.
我警告過了
I told you.
巴利
Benny.
- 把所有的人都叫來 - 「所有的人」是指什麼？
- Bring me everyone.- What do you mean, everyone?
所有的人！
Everyone!
拿著
Take this.
去看看
Go take a look.
- 別動 - 你看到什麼嗎？
- Don't move. - Do you see anything?
是那家夥，他在這 他正用槍抵著我的頭
It's the guy. He's here. He's got a gun to my head.
好，大家別輕舉妄動
Nobody moves.
- 把女孩放了 - 冷靜點，老兄！
- Let the girl go. - Take it easy, man!
把女孩放了
Let the girl go.
好，女孩出來了 放了那女孩
Okay, the girl's coming out. Let the girl go.
把牆上的斧頭拿下來 就在那堙A快去！
Grab the axe off the wall. Over there. Go!
你跟我們一起走
You're coming with us.
天啊，他開槍殺了他！
Christ, he shot him!
雜種！
Bastard!
快走！快走！
Move!
- 把水龍頭關掉 - 知道了
- Shut the fucking water off! - Got it.
快走
Come!
我們情況很不妙，派特勤隊來 重覆，派特勤隊來
We're in a bad way here. Send the cats.
我不知道發生什麼事 我沒看見他們出現，我發誓！
I don't know what happened. I didn't see 'em coming, I swear!
我買完東西回來 就到處都是他們的人
I just went shopping and I came back, and they were everywhere.
離窗口遠點
Stay away from the window.
堜龤H
Leon?
來這
Come here.
有狙擊手
Snipers.
好，現在把那個混蛋趕出來
Okay, now, get this fucking asshole out of there.
- 我們現在要如何逃走？ - 交給我，我們馬上走
- How are we gonna get outta here now? - Leave it to me. We're checking out.
但是，堜龤A這洞口你過不去 我才剛好可擠過去
But it's not big enough for you. It's barely big enough for me.
- 我們說過不准討價還價 - 不，我不要…
- We said no discussion. - No, I'm not letting--
- 我不走！我不走！ - 聽我說…
- I'm not going! I won't go! - Listen to me.
我們在一起就沒機會 但如果我一個人，就可以辦到
We have no chance together. But if I'm alone, I can do it.
相信我，我情況很好，瑪蒂達
Trust me. I'm in good shape.
我在湯尼那埵釩雃h錢
I know I've got a lot of money with Tony.
我們會拿到錢一起離開 只有我們兩個，好嗎？
We'll take it and leave together, just the two of us.
走吧
Go.
不，你這樣說是為了讓我安心
You're saying that so I won't worry.
- 我不想失去你，堜 - 你不會失去我的，瑪蒂達
- I don't wanna lose you. - You're not gonna lose me.
你讓我嘗到了人生的樂趣
You've given me a taste for life.
我想要快樂，睡在床上 有自己的根
I wanna be happy, sleep in a bed, have roots.
你永遠不會再孤獨了，瑪蒂達
You'll never be alone again.
拜托，快走，寶貝，快走
Please, go now, baby. Go.
冷靜點，快走，走
Calm down. Go now. Go.
在湯尼那堥ㄜ情A我會解決他們的 一小時後湯尼那堥
See you at Tony's. I'm gonna clean them all. Tony's in an hour.
我愛你，瑪蒂達
I love you, Mathilda.
我也愛你，堜
I love you, too, Leon.
嘿，上面怎麼回事？ 我說幹掉他，不是炸掉整棟大樓
Hey, what is going on up there? Take the guy out, not the building.
這埵陪茪H活著！
We've got one breathing here!
叫醫護人員來！
Get a medic on the horn!
讓路！讓他過去！
Clear the hall! Let him through!
- 有人受傷了，讓路！ - 走樓梯
- We've got a wounded man. Make way! - Down those stairs.
走吧！快！
Let's go! Move!
把他帶下樓梯！
Get that guy off the stairs!
帶你那一隊回到原位！
- Get your team back out there! - I got him!
有兩個人走樓梯下來了
We've got two men coming down the stairs. Let's hurry!
你沒事吧？ 嘿，這婸搨n醫護人員！
You okay? Hey, I need a medic over here!
讓開
Move your fucking asses.
第一組，公寓堭〞p如何？
Squad Number One, what's the status on the apartment?
什麼都看不見 煙太濃了，給我們五分鍾
Can't see shit. Too much smoke. Give us five minutes.
好吧
You got it.
什麼？兩百人也找不到 一個男人和一個女孩嗎？
What? Two hundred men can't find one man and a girl?
你找到那女孩了嗎？
Did you find the girl?
你感覺如何？快把面罩拿下
How are you doing? Take your mask off, quick.
讓我看看，傷口很深 這堛熄豸f…
Let me see you. That's deep. Right. And this one here--
你是第三分局的嗎？
You're from the 3rd Precinct?
好，把袖子拉開
Let's open up his sleeve a little bit.
好了，沒事的，把手放下
All right, fine. Put it down. This one.
你在這媯巨滮擱 我馬上就回來
You stay there for two minutes. I'll be right back.
讓我戴上面罩 這樣比較容易呼吸
Let me put the mask back on. I breathe better with it.
好，你說得對，坐在這塈O動
You're all right. Sit tight.
好，所有人都出去！ 快點，我們走！快點，出去！
Come on, everybody out! Let's go! Out!
讓路
Clear the way, men.
你在這媟F什麼？ 快走開
What are you doing here? Get out. Come on.
史丹菲爾德？
Stansfield?
正是
At your service.
這是…
This is from...
瑪蒂達送給你的
Mathilda.
媽的
Shit.
快離開這堙I
Get out of here!
堜靋n求我幫助你…
Leon asked me to help you out...
如果他出事的話 我想他出事了
if something happened, and I think something happened.
他留下一筆錢給你
He put aside a little cash for you.
我的建議是…
So what I'm suggesting is that...
由於你還太年輕…
seeing as how you're still so young...
錢就由我保管，直到你長大為止
I should hold the money for you until you're older.
就像銀行，你知道的，除了…
Like a bank, you know, except...
比銀行更好 因為銀行會被打劫
it's better than a bank 'cause banks always get knocked off.
但沒人敢打劫老湯尼
No one knocks off old Tony.
但這是你的錢，在這期間…
But it's your money. In the meantime...
你只須偶爾來一趟…
all you gotta do is come here every once in awhile...
我會給你一點錢，讓你玩樂一下
and I'll dish it out so you can have a little fun.
拿去
Here.
- 先給你一百塊 - 不能給我一個工作嗎？
- Here's a hundred bucks to start. - Can't I get a job instead?
工作？你能做什麼？
A job? What the hell can you do?
我會做「清潔工作」
I can clean.
我沒有工作給十二歲的小孩做…
I ain't got no work for a 12-year-old kid...
別再有這種荒唐的想法了！
so get it out of your goddamn head!
結束了！遊戲結束了！
It's over! The game's over!
堜蠾漱F！
Leon's dead!
你聽到了嗎？
You hear me?
拜托，你以為我不傷心嗎？
Come on. You think I ain't hurting too?
但他已經死了
But he's dead.
你應該忘掉這一切，回學校去 明白嗎？
You're gonna forget all this craziness and get your little ass back to school.
現在拿著錢，離開這
Now take this money and get the hell outta here.
下個月前別再讓我看到你…
Don't let me see your face till next month...
因為我快失去耐性了
'cause something tells me I'm about to lose my famous kind streak.
我的父母…
My parents...
都死了…
died...
四周前死於一場車禍
in a car accident four weeks ago.
太可怕了
It was terrible.
你剛來的時候 我們沒時間互相了解…
We didn't have the time to get to know one another when you first came here...
但我要你明白 我不是會讓孩子失望的女人…
but I want you to know I'm not the kind of woman who'd let down a child...
無論她處境如何 無論她犯了什麼錯
whatever her situation, whatever her mistake.
所以我會盡力幫助你 歡迎你回來
So I'm going to help you and do my best to welcome you here again.
但有個條件…
But on one condition:
你必須停止對我說謊，瑪蒂達
You have to stop lying to me, Mathilda.
我要你試著…
I want you to take a chance...
信任我
and trust me.
告訴我，你究竟發生了什麼事
Tell me what happened to you.
好吧
Okay.
我的家人因為毒品問題…
My family got shot down by D.E.A. officers...
被緝毒署的人殺了
because of a drug problem.
我和世上最棒的男人一起離開
I left with the greatest guy on Earth.
他是城堻抭誚y的殺手 但他今天早上死了
He was a hit man, the best in town, but he died this morning.
你不幫我的話 今晚我也會死的
If you don't help me, I'll be dead by tonight.
- 你們認識她嗎？ - 不認識
- You know her? - No.
我從沒見過她
I've never seen her.
我想我們在這媟|好好的，堜
I think we'll be okay here, Leon.